Deng-Fa, Yang (Dylan)

Location: Taiwan Telephone: (+886) 918 766 876 Website: https://dylanyang.com/ Email: dylanyang0523@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/DylanYang0523

NPM: https://www.npmjs.com/package/validate-commit-msg-regexp

Professional Profile

An engineer with a proven ability to co-work and make contributions in a team environment. Around 6 years of experience in programming. Having experience with iOS, Android development. Now mainly focusing and learning on Web development. With a passion for researching the latest technology. Careful and cautious are the biggest character traits of mine but at the same time do not cripple my efficiency and creativity.

Skills

- ReactJs
- ReduxJs
- Javascript
- Git
- GraphQL
- Docker

- NodeJs
- Webpack
- HTML5
- Sass/Css
- PostgreSQL
- ROR

- Linux
- Go
- Python
- Laravel
- MongoDB

Career Summary

*Jun 2019 - April 2020

Codegiant (Taiwan & SF)
Consultant & Sr. Developer

Outline: Optimizing the workflow and allocating the jobs properly depending on the timeline and the strong points of the engineer. Participate in a part of administration jobs.

Key Deliverables and Responsibilities:

@ Codegiant Platform (site)

- Refactoring the web front-end from class component to hook component with the new structure/features.
- Co-working with DevOp to refactor the system structure and optimize the dev env.
- Clean up the Git repository and use BFG repo-cleaner to shrink the repository's size.
- Discuss with teammates and make the decision to use Trunk Based Development (TBD) to replace Git Flow to simplify our Git working process.
- Refactoring the Git hook middleware handler from Golang to Ruby on Rails.

- Replace the Ruby on Rails thin/unicorn server with the Puma server to increase the performance and solve the thread deadlock problems.
- Upgrade Ruby on Rails from 5.2 to 6.0 and refactor the code base and structure to fit the rules of the Ruby on Rails 6.0.
- Refactoring the RESTful APIs with GraphQL (Apollo & Graphql Ruby).
- Fixing the Git related problems like Git LFS upload, repo archive, and file system problem.
- Create the system's document to help the team can set up the environment more efficiently.

@ Talentherder Platform (site)

- Let the system go live within three months.
- Write the data migration and integration script to migrate data from SqliteDB (SQL) and MongoDB (NoSQL) to PostgreSQL.
- Write Python in Jupyter Notebook to do the Mongo migration, use multiple processes and data batches to accelerate the migration process. Provide the basic bash interactive interface to separate the migration process.
- Set up the docker env inside the Linux sandbox server to run the migration.
- Refactor all APIs and features which were using the data from MongoDB or SqliteDB.
- Refactor the search feature, use data flattening, and data indexing with triggers in PostgreSQL to shrink the search response time, and implement the logical search.

*Jun 2018 - Jun 2019

CatchPlay (Taiwan) Front-end Engineer

Outline: Refactoring and optimizing the web front-end platform, including the user interface, and building with the reusable modularized product.

Key Deliverables and Responsibilities

- Integrating and developing the payment module which includes several third-party services like ECPay, LinePay... for Taiwan, Singapore, and Indonesia.
- Reducing an average of 15 API calls when a user changes the payment method and 40 API calls when the payment page is initialing.
- Participating in the whole process of the new feature "Series" development, mainly responsible for search-related features, and grid layout development's refactoring and optimization.
- Developing a Content Management System (CMS) controlled page to replace the campaign websites and increase the sign-up and paying rate.
- Co-working with data analysts and the market team for tracking and testing data on Google Tag Manager (GTM) platform.

Fun.Crea.Free (Taiwan)

Founder(Developer & Operation Focus)

Outline: Improving the project completion efficiency, increasing company revenue, and net profit. Reducing costs, and improving the operation get more fluency.

Key Deliverables and Responsibilities

- Designing project Standard Operating Procedures (SOP). From resource management, contract management, project management to code management.
- Standardizing Git commit and push management.
- Defining Eslint standards for developers to increase project manageability.
- Applying modular design patterns to fit Single Page App (SPA) to reduce communication costs between designers and engineers.
- Discussing with designers to check and revise UI/UX and user flow.
- Ability to complete projects independently and cooperatively. From the project's domain applying, IP, and server setting (AWS) to Frontend and Backend coding.
- Providing and sharing guidance to other team members on web development issues.
- Participating in discussions with clients to clarify the requirement, thereby can reduce the operating cost.
- Devising SEO strategies for clients based on specific keywords, code structure, and designs.

*Dec 2015 - Mar 2016

Tech Design (Taiwan)Web Engineer

Outline: Co-working with the market and design team to plan and refactor the main site.

Key Deliverables and Responsibilities

- Developing and maintaining the main site's front-end with Responsive Web Design (RWD).
- Refactor the part of the MySQL database schema.
- Optimize the Git repository.

*Mar 2015 - Nov 2015

Frankish International (Taiwan)
Web Engineer

Outline: Complete the project independently, including the client consulting part.

Key Deliverables and Responsibilities

Participating in the main site's planning and development.

- Develop projects independently with NodeJS, PHP, AngularJS.
- Provide consulting and advice to clients.

*Sep 2013 - Nov 2014

Tiger Party (Taiwan & NYC)Software Engineer

Outline: Co-working with Taiwan and NYC's team. Have the experience of working abroad.

Key Deliverables and Responsibilities

- Debugging and maintaining the Billboard System on NYC Times Square.
- Develop the longitude and latitude path tracking application in Android.
- Develop the media collecting application in XCode.
- Provide technical support for our clients.

Education

2009 - 2013

Fu Jen University | Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and Information Engineering

Additional Information

*Activities:

- Volunteer in earthquake and typhoon affected areas.
- School volleyball team player.

*Languages:

- Madarin(Native)
- English(Good)
- Taiwanese(Fluent)